HIT
I only came here out of respect
for my parents who...
This is a big sentence.
SPEAKER: Your father was more than just a "friend"
to my family.
♪ That was a long time ago1.
That was a long time ago2. ♪
Yes.
BANNER: Saved it for what?
- First speaker
on two lines.
- Second speaker on one line.
- Continuation of first speaker.
- Continuation of second speaker.
"He is my friend.
I will fight for him."
Of course.
"And along with that is the importance
of stronger national security.
Americans should be free to travel
safely all around the globe.
And when anyone threatens that,
they should fear our wrath."
Do you think he's capable...
of caring?
I don't want to be lied to,
and I only want to know
he's here because he's old,
unemployed, and wants
to be taken care of.