And you just need to sign here,
and here, and here.
Not that it makes a difference,
but what is it that I'm signing?
in case you fail to provide my client
with a suitable male heir.
- Suitable?
- No femmes or fatties.
This is insane.
How are you okay with this?
Kratt is a murderer.
He's holding Josh hostage.
Now, you listen to me, young lady--
And just to be clear,
we're basically the same age.
When I became a lawyer, I took an oath.
An oath called attorney-client privilege.
Which means if someone gives me money,
whatever they've done
or may do one day doesn't matter.
Bobby, how's it coming?
All good, Mr. Kratt.
Everything's signed and legally binding.
Wonderful.
You know how I feel about the law.
That it exists to protect you
and only you.
Exactly.
Thank you, Bobby. You are free to leave.
Ten dollars?
Girl, be corrupt but have some pride.
Hello, my sweet. How are you?
- Honestly, not great.
- Wedding day jitters.
Don't worry. That dress will look
much better when you're standing up.
Where is Josh? If you hurt him--
Mr. Skinner will remain unharmed
as long as you do
everything you've been asked to do.
Once we're pronounced man and wife,
he will be released, and then...
Oh, no, no, no!
Oh, don't you dare sing to me, you sicko!
I shut down a dream ballet!
I will shut down this!
Stop the music! Stop!
But unfortunately, that someone isn't me.
My heart belongs to Josh,
and it always will,
and there's nothing you can do
to change that.
The wedding is in one hour.
See you at the altar.
Frau.
Maybe I was once,
but that was a long time ago.
I did what I had to do to survive.
I recommend you do the same.
Mr. Kratt is the wealthiest man
in Schmicago.
You will be comfortable, taken care of.
And in a place like this,
that's not nothing.
So, you see... ...we actually didn't even want to be here.
We were just trying
to get back to Schmigadoon.
It's kind of funny
when you think about it.
You enjoyed your freedom while you had it.
Now it's time you pay your dues
like the rest of us.
- Like the rest of you?
- Guys like you are lucky.
You and your hippie friends,
you get to live however you like
while slobs like me
get stuck doing all the work.
What's stopping you
from living the life you want?
Hello. Uncle Octavius.
There's been a slight change of plans.
After the wedding,
you need to kill Mr. Skinner.
But I thought the plan was to release him.
Plans change.
You need to kill him.
It will make it easier
for my new bride to move on.
Okay. But if I do, will I finally get
my own act at the club like you promised?
I-I don't know
if you saw my latest proposal, but--
Kill him.
What was that about?
Wrong number.
You literally said, "Uncle Octavius."
So now you're just going to kill me?
I'm sure you've got things in your job
you don't like.
Don't do this.
It's not worth it.
- Uncle Octavius will make it worth it.
- How do you know?
Because he's been promising me
for the past 36 years. That's how.
S-- Have you ever heard of
the Parable of the Faithful Servant?
- The what?
- Mmm.
There once was a faithful servant
who served a cruel master.
The master kept asking the servant
to do things for him
that the servant knew in his heart
w-were wrong.
But he did them
because he had been promised
that he would inherit all of
his master's riches when he died.
But when the master finally died,
the servant discovered
that he left everything to his new
totally age-inappropriate wife.
And the servant ended up with nothing
but his own broken dreams.
The end.
I see what you're trying to do,
and it's not gonna work.
Besides, it's too late for me.
It's never too late
to follow your dreams, man.
Have you heard the parable of
the guy who helped the other guy,
and it worked out for both of them?
Gobble, gobble, gobble.
Fill up those tummies.
I need an orphan! Now!
- But the plan.
- The plan failed.
That devil Kratt
has eluded my grasp once again.
Mercy, what happened?
What happened? He's alive.
My Daisy's dead.
My blade requires blood.
So, who wants to go first?
Now, now. Let's not get hasty here.
- Let's wait until--
- No more waiting!
You claim to be devoted to me,
Miss Codwell.
Well, now's the time to prove it.
God, that was good.
Come with me.
Nap time! Everybody needs a nap! Now!
Do as you're told.
What do you want?
- Is everything okay?
- We heard screaming.
Did that man harm you?
Are you in danger?
Why'd you call him daddy?
No, I'm fine. We're fine.
Go back to your rooms.
No one's in any danger.
Actually, that's not quite true, my sweet.
Last night, I saw Mr. Skinner
being taken at gunpoint
by that crooked policeman, Rivera.
How can we help him?
We don't even know where he is.
The same place Rivera took me
20 years ago for questioning.
The basement of Kratt's power plant.
You may get to kill someone yet.
Well, if providence is kind.
That was amazing.
It's so nice for once to get to be
the student instead of the teacher.
Do you think there's even more
for me to learn about lovemaking?
Yeah, definitely.
It was great.
But, you know, even--
even Picasso kept taking lessons.
You know, there's always,
uh, more to learn.
- Go away!
- Come on.
Well. At least you're still getting naked.
What do you want?
Shouldn't you be out
following your new chosen leader, Josh?
Josh is in trouble.
Sergeant Rivera took him
to the power plant
so they can force Melissa to marry Kratt.
- We obviously don't care about Melissa...
- No.
...but we didn't know what to do,
so we came to you.
It's true Josh hurt me.
But sometimes, when your face
has been slapped,
you need to turn the other cheek
and let that person slap you again.
- But do you?
- Yeah, that sounds bad.
- Yeah, not the best example, darling.
- Oh.
But no matter what he did,
Josh is still our chum.
And if he needs our help, then we need to
be there for him no matter what.
You better gas up the happiness bus.
It's on.
Yes!
Let's roll.
And not only did Sloth set Chunk free
and get revenge on his evil family,
but he became friends with all the Goonies
and shared in their bounteous fortune.
- The end.
- Good.
Start one more parable
and I'll kill you right now.
No, you won't.
Let Josh go now.
Topher?
Josh. I'm so sorry, man.
A sour macaroon?
I don't even know what that means.
No worries. I love you, man.
- I love you too, man.
- Oh, brother.
If it isn't our troupe of
strolling fruitcakes come to save the day.
With what? Love?
Nice try. I've got this.
Wait.
Love is stronger than any gun.
Are you sure about that?
I'm not sure about that, no.
That's right, copper.
- And who the hell are you?
- You don't recognize me, Sergeant Rivera?
Well, I suppose I can't blame you.
It has been 20 years
since you sent me to prison
for the murder of my wife, Daisy.
Dooley Blight?
In the flesh.
And thirsty for revenge.
Wait.
Daisy was my mother's name.
Hello, my daughter.
No.
I have no father.
Jenny. Jenny, believe me,
I never harmed your mother.
I loved her more than life itself.
I wish I could believe that, but I don't.
I want nothing to do with you.
Then I may as well
leave this hell for the next.
- No!
- Stop! Stop!
He's telling the truth.
And I know...
because I'm the one who framed him.
Kratt killed your mother, not Dooley.
Who wants to help me stop a wedding?
I do!
Do you, Octavius, take Melissa
to be your lawful wedded wife?
I do.
Do you, Melissa, take Octavius
to be your lawful wedded husband?
I have no choice.
That counts!
Then by the power vested in me
by the city of Schmicago,
I pronounce you ma--
- Stop the wedding!
- Josh!
You. How did you--
You need to shut your stupid mouth
and get away from my wife.
- Seize him.
- What?
Officers, stand down!
What do you think you're doing?
Standing up to you. For once.
And so am I.
Enough is enough, Octavius!
I'm afraid the two of you
have overplayed your hand.
They don't answer to you.
They answer to me.
I love you, Mel!
And I'm so sorry for this whole mess!
I love you too! No matter what happens,
I'll always love you!
Enough of this prattle.
Pronounce us man and wife.
By the power vested in me by the city of
Schmicago, I now pronounce you--
- Vengeance!
- Dooley Blight?
- Is mine!
- No, Daddy, no!
You just keep on losing,
don't you, Blight?
Not so fast, my sweet.
Finish the ceremony.
Mr. Kratt, as your lawyer, I must advise--
Myself to sit back down.
Finish it!
Okay, um, then by the power vested in me
by the city Schmicago,
- I pronounce you man and--
- Look up!
Oh, shit.
Seriously? Again?
It really is a wonderful knife.
My love.
- Are you all right? - Yeah, I am now.
- I love you.
Is he dead?
Now that Kratt is dead, things are
about to change in Schmicago.
Madam Frau will take over the club
and use her position
to promote exciting new talent.
Like ex-Sergeant Rivera.
Bobby will team up with the tribe
to split up Kratt's monopolies,
and something incredible will happen.
They all get jobs!
While Topher and Jenny will find
the perfect home for their talents
at the orphanage.
Because Miss Codwell and Dooley
will go into business together
and make a killing.
So, Josh and Melissa now finally have
the happy ending they've been seeking
and are free to leave Schmicago and go
back to their world.
But why would they?
Why return to a place
you were so desperate to leave?
Where bad people triumph,
good people suffer,
and some couples,
no matter how badly they want it,
will never ever have children?
Sure, you-- You probably feel
like you've learned something
on your brief sojourn here.
And now life is gonna be so much better.
Right?
Didn't you feel that way
when you left Schmigadoon?
That you had gotten your happy ending,
that everything was gonna be okay
from here on out?
But it wasn't, was it?
The magic wore off.
Magic always does,
except here in Schmicago.
- Here you could be a star.
- A beloved leader.
Here all of your dreams
can actually come true.
Thanks to you, things are
getting better here for all of us.
You can't leave now.
Things are just getting good!
Add 'em up, kiddos. Add 'em up.
So, what's it gonna be?
The joyless drudgery of life out there?
Or the magic and excitement here?
What are you thinking?
I think...
More what?
More uncertainty? More joylessness?
The only place you're gonna get
what you really want is here.
All of you.
But it's time for us to go.
Are you sure?
It's gonna be a constant struggle
with more bad days than good ones.
And a very good chance you'll end up
right back where you were.
We know.
You did it! You did it! I knew you would!
I knew you had it in you!
What?
I'm so sorry putting you through all this.
I really am, but I had to test you.
And you passed the test, didn't ya!
Wait, you're smiling? Why are you smiling?
- Because he works for me.
- For you?
Yeah, about that.
I'm not doing this narrator gig no more.
I'm tired of helping people
figure out their lives.
I want a life of my own! With romance!
And it's gonna be with... him.
I don't hate it.
And that's the moment
the Narrator's life changed.
Okay, I'm happy for you.
Thank you.
So, can we go home now?
You can go home, yes, you can go home,
but that's just the beginning!
What's more important
is what you'll take with you when you go!
Wait a minute. Is-- Isn't that--
My brother.
He's a little more traditional than I am,
but I still love the guy.
- Shall we, Oscar?
- Of course, Steve.